okay right well good morning and welcome
好的，好的，早上好，欢迎光临
after so it's really good to see so many
这么多以后真的很高兴
people here at half past eight in the
这里的人八点半
morning
早上
bit of an early start I know last night
昨晚我有点早起
number of parties but what we can do
参加人数，但我们能做些什么
this morning is talk about streams in
今天早上正在谈论溪流
JDK eight and we've kind of titled this
JDK八，我们以此命名
the good the bad and the ugly and the
好，坏，丑，
idea of this presentation is really to
这个演讲的想法真的是为了
sort of help you learn from my mistakes
您从我的错误中学到的帮助
not Stuart's my mistakes and what we're
不是斯图亚特的错误，也是我们的错误
going to do is we can look at some
我们要做的就是看一些
samples of streams code and really this
流代码示例，实际上这
is kind of tracking some of my learning
有点跟踪我的学习情况
process about streams and understanding
关于流和理解的过程
how you need to think differently
您需要如何思考
because as Java programmers we are very
因为作为Java程序员，我们非常
much focused on imperative programming
非常关注命令式编程
we understand the idea of loops we
我们了解循环的想法
understand the idea of mutable state so
了解可变状态的想法
we put things in variables so if I ask
我们把东西放在变量中，所以如果我问
show of hands who here thinks they're a
在这里以为自己是举手的人
Java programmer okay that's good we have
Java程序员，好的，我们有
the right audience who here would
合适的听众
describe themselves as a functional
将自己描述为功能
programmer yes you see there's only a
程序员，是的，你看到只有一个
few people here and that's that's the
这里的人很少，那就是
key thing here is that functional
这里的关键是功能
programming is very different to
编程与
imperative programming and you do need
命令式编程，您确实需要
to think differently so we're going to
换个角度思考，所以我们要
give you some examples of how to not do
给你一些不怎么做的例子
things as well as how to do things and
事情以及如何去做，
really the sort of idea behind this
真的是这个背后的想法
presentation came about because I wrote
因为我写了演讲
a blog entry where I explained about how
一个博客条目，我在其中解释了如何
I'd done some things with streams and
我用流做了一些事情，
somebody didn't like my code and he kind
有人不喜欢我的代码，他很友善
of criticized it and so we had a
被批评了，所以我们有一个
discussion about that and so this is
关于这个的讨论，所以这是
kind of how we came about this
我们是怎么想到的
presentation so first I should introduce
介绍，所以首先我应该介绍
so I'm Simon Ritter I work for is all
所以我是我工作的Simon Ritter
I'm I'm Stuart marks I work for Oracle
我是Stuart标志着我在Oracle工作
on the JDK core libraries yes so Stuart
是在JDK核心库上，所以Stuart
obviously has had a lot to do with the
显然与
development of streams I haven't
我还没有开发流
okay so the first thing was was dealing
好吧，所以第一件事就是
with exceptions because this actually is
有例外，因为这实际上是
something which can be quite tricky when
在什么时候可能会非常棘手
it comes to using screens as we will see
我们将看到使用屏幕
now the problem that I had was I was
现在我的问题是
trying to process some data that was
试图处理一些原本是
coming through like a sort of web
像网络一样穿越
interface and so the idea is you've got
界面，所以您的想法就是
a very simple you know key value set
一个非常简单的键值集
that you want to extract information
您要提取信息的
from so simple thing in few action is
从这么简单的事情，很少采取行动是
validate key is 10 key is 22 key is 10
验证键是10键是22键是10
key is 33 so what I wanted was results
关键是33，所以我想要的是结果
in the form of action and validate and
以行动和验证的形式
then key where I had a set of values 10
然后键，我有一组值10
22 10 and 33 so the important thing is
22 10和33所以重要的是
that I could have duplicate values in
我可以在其中重复值
the set that I've got that would that
我所拥有的那个
was actually quite a an important point
实际上是很重要的一点
so of course the first thing I do is I
所以我要做的第一件事当然是
go to stack overflow and I say has
去堆栈溢出，我说有
anybody faced this problem before and I
任何人以前都遇到过这个问题，我
look around and I find that yes
环顾四周，我发现是的
somebody has produced a nice peat well a
有人生产了一个很好的泥炭
piece of code which does this now we're
现在执行此操作的一段代码
not going to talk about this because
不打算谈论这个，因为
this is obviously it's rather small and
这显然很小，而且
it's actually not a very nice piece of
这实际上不是一个很好的部分
code even I would have to admit that
代码，甚至我不得不承认
there's a lot of things in this code
这段代码中有很多东西
that could be tidied up and improved so
可以整理和改善
we won't talk about that other than to
我们除了谈论别的
say that I've looked at that and I
说我已经看过了，我
thought to myself no I don't want to do
对自己想，不，我不想做
it that way I want to use streams so I
这样我想使用流，所以我
came up with this and the the thing that
想出了这个和那个东西
I was really focused on which I
我真的很专注于
shouldn't have been was making this as
不应该一直这样
compact as possible so I want you to
尽可能紧凑，所以我要你
squeeze us into literally three lines of
将我们挤进字面上的三行
code so as you can see here I have come
代码，如您所见，我来了
up with Perl because it's rather dense
与Perl联系起来，因为它非常密集
and it's not actually the best kind of
这实际上不是最好的
code
码
so there are three problems with this
所以这有三个问题
and in fact I I came up with two
实际上，第二个想出了两个
problems and then Stewart pointed out
问题，然后斯图尔特指出
there was a third problem associated
还有第三个问题
with this the three problems are that
与此相关的三个问题是
this can return a null so that's you
这可以返回空值，就是你
know never a good idea because if you
永远不知道一个好主意，因为如果你
return and now then you're gonna have to
返回，现在您将不得不
test for the null when you get the
当您得到
result and deal with it appropriately so
结果并适当处理
returning and I'll not a good idea
回来，我不是一个好主意
especially since we have an optional in
特别是因为我们有一个可选的
JDK 8
JDK 8
the second thing is that split this is
第二件事是拆分这是
one that Stewart pointed out to me
斯图尔特向我指出的那个
recently split is called twice so we're
最近被分割了两次，所以我们
doing the same thing
做同样的事情
calling split twice and that's very
叫两次分裂，这是非常
inefficient so we need to resolve that
效率低下，所以我们需要解决
problem and then third thing is it
问题，然后是第三件事
doesn't call the URL decode decode
不调用URL解码解码
method which is used in the original
原来使用的方法
code and the reason for that was because
代码，其原因是因为
I didn't want to have to deal with the
我不想面对
exception because the problem is that
例外，因为问题是
decode throws a checked exception and if
解码抛出一个检查异常，如果
you're using a stream and using the
您正在使用流，并使用
stream API you can't throw an exception
流API，您不能抛出异常
out of the stream method so do you want
流方法之外，您要
to just yeah a couple things on that so
只是在这上面几件事
so one is yeah so the original code had
所以是的，所以原始代码有
this had this interesting thing and this
这个有这个有趣的东西，这个
isn't particularly about streams but
不是特别关于流，但是
it's it's it's about general code and as
这是关于通用代码的
we improve the code in general it
我们一般会改进代码
actually makes streams much much nicer
实际上使流更好
to deal with but in this particular case
处理，但在这种情况下
the the original code accepted a null
原始代码接受了null
and it had to test it and if it if the
它必须测试它，如果
input was null a returned null and and
输入为null，返回null，并且
it's like everybody does that and that's
就像每个人都那样
that's sort of a strange thing to do if
如果这是一件奇怪的事情
you think about it because what you want
您考虑一下，因为您想要什么
is a value which is a map from string to
是一个值，它是从字符串到
string Kalista string and you want to
字符串Kalista字符串，你想
process those and so if you have this I
处理那些，所以如果你有这个我
think it's a bad coding habit Trisha gee
认为这是一种不良的编码习惯Trisha gee
wrote a blog post a few weeks ago at the
几周前在
JetBrains
JetBrains
she has a blog series about code smells
她有一个关于代码气味的博客系列
where she talks about no and it turns
她说不的地方就变成了
out the code base she was she was
在代码库中，她是
working on every method said oh if I get
尝试每种方法都说哦，如果我明白了
null return null and even if that didn't
null返回null，即使没有
make sense at all it was sort of a bad
完全是有道理的
habit that was propagated throughout the
在整个世界传播的习惯
code base and I think that's kind of
代码库，我认为这是
what's going on here because if you
这是怎么回事，因为如果你
think think about the context here
考虑一下这里的背景
you're you have a URL and you want to
你有一个URL，你想
grab the arguments off the end of the
抓住论点的末尾
URL so if there are any arguments then
URL，因此如果有任何参数
that you have a non-empty string if
您有一个非空字符串，如果
there aren't any arguments then maybe
然后没有任何争论
you should have an empty string but you
你应该有一个空字符串，但是你
should never have null so where does
永远不应该为null，所以在哪里
null come from right and then so if you
null来自右，然后如果您
if you think about getting rid of nulls
如果您考虑摆脱空值
you never return null should return an
你永远不会返回null应该返回一个
empty map instead and then whatever
空的地图，而不是然后
meets the processes it will process
符合将要处理的流程
every entry of the empty map which
空图的每个条目
we'll just do nothing so you just so
我们什么也不会做，所以你就是这样
you'd really try to think about when you
你真的会想想你什么时候
really need to process null and when
真的需要处理null和何时
it's just a bad habit of oh I better
这只是一个坏习惯，哦，我更好
check for null and return null oh and
检查null并返回null哦，然后
then one quick thing here to the
然后在这里快速做一件事
original code had a regular expression
原始代码有一个正则表达式
in the split command which actually
在split命令中
slows it down quite a bit because it's
放慢了速度，因为
all it's doing is matching a single
它要做的就是匹配一个
character so there's actually a fast
角色，所以实际上有一个快
path in the split method it takes a
split方法中的路径需要一个
regular expression but if it says oh if
正则表达式，但是如果它说哦，如果
I'm splitting on a single character goes
我正在分裂一个角色
through a completely different section
通过完全不同的部分
of code that bypasses all the expensive
绕过所有昂贵的代码
regular expression processing so it goes
正则表达式处理
much faster good to know okay so then
快很多，知道就可以了
obviously after a bit of discussion with
经过一番讨论之后
it Stewart I came up with a better
斯图尔特我想出了一个更好的
approach and so the idea here is to to
方法，所以这里的想法是
extract some of the code out into a
提取一些代码到一个
method here what we're going to do is
方法，我们要做的是
we're going to split the key and the
我们将拆分密钥和
value and that way we can use the URL
值，这样我们就可以使用网址
decoded decode method and we can deal
解码的解码方法，我们可以处理
with the exception but we have to do
除了例外，我们必须做
that in the method so we have to somehow
在方法中，所以我们必须以某种方式
deal with the exception the checked
处理检查的异常
exception in that method and so you know
该方法中的异常，所以你知道
it's it comes down to the design of the
这取决于设计
streams API and I'm spoken to Brian
流API，我和Brian谈过
about this in the past about the digit
关于这个过去的数字
yes yeah brackets yeah yeah about you
是的，是括号，是的，关于您
know the way that you don't have the
知道你没有的方式
ability to throw an exception out of a
从一个异常中抛出异常的能力
stream because ideally what we'd like to
流，因为理想情况下我们想要
be able to do is have a stream and then
能够做的是有一个流，然后
at some point something happens in a
在某个时候
lambo Xpression you throw an exception
兰博Xpression您抛出异常
and then that gets thrown out of the
然后将其扔出
whole stream but it just doesn't work
整个流，但这只是行不通
that way so what what we have to do is
这样我们要做的就是
we have to have a method and in this
我们必须要有一种方法
case we have to do something in terms of
情况下，我们必须做一些事情
dealing with that exception so we call
处理该异常，所以我们称
the dqo method it could potentially
dqo方法可能
throw exception in this case we're going
在这种情况下抛出异常
to do a a warning from the logger and
从记录器发出警告
we'll return null the other thing about
我们将返回null另一件事
this is that it uses a JDK 9 enhancement
这是因为它使用了JDK 9增强功能
which is met map dot entry so map dot
遇到地图点输入，因此地图点
entry will return you well a map entry
条目将为您返回一张地图条目
the nice thing about that is that you
那件事的好处是你
don't have to use there's a kind of
不必使用有一种
class which is buried in was abstract
埋葬的类是抽象的
abstract map that simple immutable entry
简单的不可变条目的抽象映射
yes abstract map dot simple immutable
是的，抽象的地图点简单不可变
entry as opposed to the class which we
进入而不是我们的阶级
should have which is called tuple and so
应该有所谓的元组等等
so we ended up with this where we
所以我们最终在这里
actually return a map taught entry and
实际返回地图教导的条目，并且
we get one which is a string in a string
我们得到一个字符串中的一个字符串
so so we extract out the code that needs
所以我们提取出需要的代码
to deal with the exception into a
处理异常
separate method and then in terms of
分开的方法，然后就
actually making our code nicer we end up
实际上使我们的代码更好，我们最终
with this where obviously we made it a
有了这个，显然我们做到了
little bit bigger but it's much easier
更大一点，但是要容易得多
to read so now we have the idea we're
阅读，所以现在我们有了主意
going to pause the query we we create a
要暂停查询，我们创建一个
stream based on splitting on the
流基于拆分
ampersand and then we filter to ensure
＆符，然后我们进行过滤以确保
that we don't get any non null or any
我们不会得到任何非null或任何
null objects so that's a simple way of
空对象，这是一种简单的方法
eliminating that problem of the null
消除了null问题
obviously at that point because we're
显然在那个时候，因为我们
calling objects dot require non null if
调用对象点要求非null
it's a null ill throw a null pointer
这是一个空病，抛出空指针
exception but that is at least a better
例外，但这至少是一个更好的选择
way of potentially dealing with it
潜在的处理方式
because did you want to say anything
因为你想说什么
about that yeah oh yeah when you're
关于那是的，哦，是的，当你
finished I'll go back to the previously
完成后，我将回到先前
okay the opposite so we eliminate the
好吧，相反，所以我们消除了
problem having null in terms of our
关于我们的null问题
value then we call the map and we use
值，然后我们调用地图，然后使用
our split key value which is the one
我们的分割键值是
that we've extracted out the the code
我们已经提取了代码
that deals with the exception then we
处理异常，然后我们
found filth of that to say if that
发现污秽的东西说
returns our null then we just ignore
返回我们的null，然后我们忽略
anything because obviously that's not
任何事情，因为显然那不是
the information we need so we can
我们需要的信息，以便我们可以
eliminate that and then we use a collect
消除它，然后我们使用收集
reduction so we're grouping by the key
减少，所以我们按键分组
and the value
和价值
and generating a list so it's a lot
并生成一个列表，所以很多
clearer
更清晰
Oh Nita lot tidier Vann the three lines
哦尼塔很多整理者范三行
of code that I tried to write originally
我最初尝试编写的代码
so if I go back to the previous slide
所以如果我回到上一张幻灯片
okay yeah a couple comments on this so
好吧，对此有几个评论
so as Simon pointed out the the the
正如西蒙指出的
there's a there's a problem here because
这里有一个问题，因为
there's a mismatch between AP is in the
AP之间存在不匹配
jdk that throw checked exceptions and
抛出检查异常的JDK和
using those api's in streams which
在流中使用这些api
generally do not allow checked
通常不允许检查
exceptions and so the sad thing about
例外，所以关于
this is i went back and revisited this
这是我回去回顾这个
this it's actually totally unnecessary
这实际上完全没有必要
to have a checked exception in this case
在这种情况下具有检查异常
but the the bug is actually missing
但是错误实际上是缺失的
api's in the jdk so so if you dig into
api在jdk中，所以如果您深入研究
this what's going on is so it's the URL
这是怎么回事，所以这是URL
decode or decode method throws this
解码或解码方法抛出此
unsupported encoding exception that's
不支持的编码异常是
because you have to tell it what
因为你必须告诉它什么
encoding it uses and the way you tell it
对其使用的编码以及告诉方式
what encoding to use is by giving it the
给它使用什么编码
string name of an encoding and so
编码的字符串名称等等
there's the possibility that the
有可能
encoding for that string name that you
该字符串名称的编码
give it is not present and that's
给它不存在，那是
actually kind of an old-fashioned API
实际上是一种老式的API
those those were introduced very early
那些很早被介绍的
on in the JDK much more recently a bunch
最近在JDK中
of the api's have been added there's a
的api的已添加
there's a char set object and there are
有一个字符集对象，还有
char set constants like charset utf-8
像charset utf-8这样的char设置常量
and that's present everywhere so there's
那无处不在，所以
this oh yeah somebody has points that
哦，是的，有人指出
standard char sets yes so so so anyway
标准字符集是的，所以还是这样
so the those are guaranteed to be
所以那些保证是
present in the JDK and so if you use a
存在于JDK中，因此如果您使用
char set object then you can often call
字符集对象，那么您可以经常调用
an API and pass the char set object and
一个API并传递char set对象，然后
it doesn't throw a checked exception
它不会引发检查异常
unfortunately there is no such overload
不幸的是，没有这样的超载
for URL decode or decode and also for
用于URL解码或解码，也用于
encode so really what we need to do is
如此编码，实际上我们需要做的是
fix up the api's and then this this
修复api，然后这个
whole segment of the problem should go
问题的整个部分都应该走
away and then there's another problem
离开，然后还有另一个问题
which which is I'm not entirely sure but
我不确定哪一个，但是
if we're decoding the URL the the actual
如果我们要解码网址，则实际
character encoding is I think officially
我认为字符编码是正式的
unspecified but it's usually utf-8 so
未指定，但通常是utf-8，因此
you might be able to get away if you had
如果有的话，您也许可以逃脱
a better API you might be able to get
您可能可以获得更好的API
away with specifying utf-8 here then you
在这里指定utf-8，然后您
avoid the whole checked exception and in
避免整个检查异常
fact then you could refactor the whole
事实上，您可以重构整个
thing and and it would get much nicer
东西，它将变得更好
but we do not have that option today but
但是我们今天没有那个选择，但是
somebody remind me to file a bug for
有人提醒我为
that
那
okay one more thing oh and then also
好吧，再一件事哦，然后
there's this split method so so
有这种拆分方法，所以
basically that you essentially want key
基本上，您本质上想要钥匙
value pairs and we split on equals and
值对，我们在等号和
so there's this issue here which is so
所以这里有一个问题
we use the the overload of split which
我们使用split的重载
takes a limit argument so that means if
接受一个极限参数，这意味着如果
they're multiple equal sign in one
他们是多个等号
string we take the the first chunk to
字符串，我们将第一个块
the left of the first equal sign and
第一个等号的左侧和
call that the key and the rest of the
称钥匙和其余的
string is the value even if it includes
字符串是值，即使它包含
equal signs but there's still a bug here
等号，但这里仍然有错误
which is if the chunk we get has no
如果我们得到的块没有
equal sign this will return an array of
等号，这将返回一个数组
length one and actually we'll throw up
长度一，实际上我们会吐
array index out of bounds exception so
数组索引超出范围异常
so anyway so there's there's a lot of
所以无论如何，有很多
stuff going on in this code you have to
这段代码中发生的事情
think about but all right well but we
想一想，但是很好，但是我们
should move on yeah wise did you want to
你应该继续前进吗？
talk about the second slide I think no
说说第二张幻灯片
I'm sure he's going right okay so next
我确定他会没事的，所以接下来
thing is imperative screams if we can
如果可以的话，当务之急是尖叫
hold questions until the end ya know if
一直等到最后，你知道是否
we keep questions till the end because
我们将问题一直保留到最后，因为
we got quite a lot to get through so we
我们有很多事情要做，所以我们
don't were kind of pause too much
不要太停顿
okay so imperative streams now this
好吧，当务之急现在这
comes back to what I was saying about
回到我在说什么
how as Java developers we tend to think
作为Java开发人员，我们倾向于如何思考
imperatively we think in terms of loops
我们必须从循环的角度进行思考
and so when JDK 8 first came out I
所以当JDK 8第一次问世时
decided to write some code that would
决定写一些代码
scan through all the Java Doc's and find
扫描所有Java文档并查找
all places where you had a method to
您有办法的所有地方
returned a stream and all the places
返回了一条小溪和所有地方
where you had a method that would take
你有办法采取的方法
an argument which is a functional
一个功能性的论点
interface and therefore I could use a
界面，因此我可以使用
lambda expression because there was no
lambda表达式，因为没有
kind of sick sink list that was
那种病态的水槽清单
available so I did that and I thought
可用，所以我做到了，我想
right I'm gonna use streams to write
对，我要用流写
this code and one of the bits of code I
此代码和代码的位I
ended up with was where I want to count
最后是我想数的地方
how many new or how many class I'm sorry
抱歉，有多少个新班或多少个班
how many methods there were which
有多少种方法
returned a stream so I had a map of
返回了一条小溪，所以我有一张地图
classes two methods and so what I wanted
类两个方法，所以我想要什么
to be able to do is go through that and
能够做的就是经历
count up how many there were so I came
数一数所以我来了
up with this piece of code and I said
这段代码，我说
okay let's take out our map and then
好吧，我们拿出地图，然后
we'll get the class from that and we'll
我们将从中得到课程，我们将
create a stream from that and then
从中创建一个流，然后
each of those I need to do something so
每个人我都需要这样做
what I want to do is I'm going to print
我要做的是打印
out the the method and then I want to
出方法，然后我想
count if this is a new method so I
数一下这是否是一种新方法，所以我
thought to myself okay so I know that
自以为还好，所以我知道
this could potentially be multi-threaded
这可能是多线程的
so I'm going to use a long adder which
所以我要使用一个长加法器
is specifically designed for this type
专为此类型设计
of situation where you got frequent
你经常去的情况
writes and infrequent reads so each
写和不常读，所以每个
thread gets its own instance of the
线程获取自己的实例
variable you can update them
变量，您可以更新它们
independently there's no contention
独立没有争执
there locking and then when you need the
那里锁定，然后当您需要
result it brings it all together so I
结果将所有东西都融合在一起，所以我
thought that's a really good thing to do
认为这是一件非常好的事
it's new and JDK 8 will use that so I
它是新的，JDK 8将使用它，所以我
ended up with this very nice piece of
最终得到了非常不错的
code where I said okay take the stream
我说好的代码流
do for each and then I'll take my method
为每个做，然后我会采取我的方法
name and then I printed out a check of
名称，然后我打印出一张支票
its new method and then I'll increment
它的新方法，然后我将增加
it okay so I spoke to the steward about
没关系，所以我跟管家谈了一下
this and he said ah well you see that's
这个，他说啊，你看那是
not functional programming this is very
没有函数式编程这是非常
bad this is not functional programming
不好，这不是函数式编程
so I thought okay I'll go with and I'll
所以我想我会和我一起去
have another go at that so I thought
还有另一件事，所以我想
right
对
I don't need stating this in terms of
我不需要以
external state so what I'll do is I'll
外部状态，所以我要做的是
make it a little bit more complicated
使它更加复杂
and I'll come up with the idea that I
然后我会想到
create my stream and obviously I should
创建我的流，显然我应该
have shifted this out into a method but
已经将其转移到方法中，但是
I'll put it in here just to make it
我把它放在这里只是为了
easier to see on one slide and I'll say
更容易在一张幻灯片上看到，我会说
take the method and then I'll have a
采取方法，然后我将有一个
variable inside my lambda expression
我的lambda表达式中的变量
which is new method is zero then I'll
这是新的方法是零然后我会
print out the method and then I'll check
打印出方法，然后我将检查
see if it's a new method if it is I'll
看看这是否是一种新方法
set a new method be one I mean I'll just
设定一种新方法我就是说
return a new method so I get a stream of
返回一个新方法，所以我得到了
ones and zeros and I add those up and I
一和零，我加起来，我
get a count of how many new methods
计算出多少种新方法
there are which do what I want so again
有哪些我想再做一次
I showed this to Stuart he said well
我告诉斯图尔特他说得很好
yeah you see this is this is kind of a
是的，你看到这是一种
bit more functional but it's not
有点功能，但不是
functional because we've still got state
起作用，因为我们仍然有状态
involved so even though we've taken the
即使我们采取了
state internally we're still modifying
在内部说明我们仍在修改
state so strictly speaking I mean you
这么严格地说我的意思是你
know as a function it would work because
知道它会起作用，因为
you could put apply the same input and
您可以应用相同的输入并
get the same output no matter how many
不管有多少，都得到相同的输出
times but there still be state being
时代，但仍然有状态
modified so that's not the way to do it
修改，所以这不是做到这一点的方法
so I thought okay I'll go well have
所以我以为我会很好
another go at this and so I came up with
另一个去，所以我想出了
a better way of doing it which is almost
一种更好的方法，几乎
functional but not quite so again we
功能正常，但事实并非如此
take the stream and then we use this
走流，然后我们用这个
this handy little method called peak
这个方便的小方法称为Peak
peak allows you to look at the elements
峰值让您看一下元素
of the stream as they go past and so
流过时的水流等
long as you don't modify them you can
只要不修改它们，就可以
you can look at them and you can do
你可以看着他们，你可以做
something like print them out so I could
像打印出来的东西，所以我可以
print out the the method names as they
打印出方法名称
were getting passed and then I passed
过去了，然后我过去了
that to map tint and no state involved
映射色调，不涉及任何状态
in terms of having a variable and I
就拥有变量而言，我
thought right I'll use the conditional
认为正确，我将使用条件
operator and I'll say if it's a new
运算符，我会说是不是新的
method return 1 otherwise return 0 so I
方法返回1，否则返回0，所以我
still get my stream of zeros and ones
仍然得到我的零和一流
and I sum those up and I get my result
我总结这些，我得到了结果
and then Stewart pointed out well
然后斯图尔特指出得很好
actually there's a slightly better way
其实有一个更好的方法
of doing that which is to use a filter
使用过滤器的过程
so rather than you know doing an if
所以而不是你知道如果
statement inside a map to int why not
映射到int内的语句为什么不
use a filter because I thought it takes
使用过滤器，因为我认为这需要
a predicate and a predicate is an if
predicate和predicate是if
statement so we can do it that way and
声明，这样我们就可以做到
we end up with filter M goes to is new
我们最终将过滤器M转到新的
method and then we pass it to count
方法，然后将其传递给计数
rather than sum and everything works so
而不是总和，所以一切正常
this is all very good so this looks I
这一切都很好，所以看起来我
think it's myself look this is
认为这是我自己的样子
functional code we have done really well
我们做得很好的功能代码
here and then Stuart said no it is not
在这里，然后斯图亚特说不，不是
functional code he said
他说的功能代码
strictly speaking print line is side
严格来说，打印线是侧面
effect and if you're being purely
效果，如果你是纯粹的
functional you can't have side effects
功能，你不会有副作用
so I'm gonna hand it over to Stuart - ok
所以我要交给斯图尔特-好的
all right so yeah that was quite a quite
好的，是的，那是相当不错的
an evolution there and I think that's
那里的演变，我认为那是
true and I think that I think peak using
是的，我认为我使用了
peak for printing out logging is a fine
打印输出日志的高峰很好
thing to do this is kind of a debugging
要做的事情是一种调试
thing I guess if you want to actually
我想如果你真的想
store the results somewhere you probably
将结果存储在您可能所在的位置
should build them up in a data structure
应该将它们建立在数据结构中
using a collector or something like that
使用收集器或类似的东西
we have examples of that later on but I
我们以后会有例子
just wanted to reflect on the the very
只是想反省
beginning of this I don't know if you
开始我不知道你是否
want to mind back to the to the first
想介意回到第一个
slide of this
这个幻灯片
so you see that there's a lot of
所以你看到有很多
evolution of the stream going on here
流在这里演变
and that one okay
那还好
so Simon started off with four each and
所以西蒙开始时各有四个
the the problem with four each is that
每个有四个的问题是
it's it's the easiest stream function to
这是最简单的流功能
understand but it's actually probably
了解，但实际上可能
one of the least useful ones because I
最不有用的之一，因为我
think I don't want to harp on you too
认为我也不想对你竖琴
much but I think Simon fell into this
很多，但我认为西蒙陷入了这个
trap which is there's all this there's
陷阱就是所有这一切
all this weird stuff well for each well
所有这些奇怪的东西都很好
I know what that does so I'll start
我知道会做什么，所以我将开始
writing with for each and the problem
与每个问题一起写作
with for each is that and immediately
与每个是和立即
leads you into side-effects and once
导致你产生副作用
you've fallen into the trap of
你陷入了陷阱
side-effects then you really have to
副作用，那么您真的必须
think differently about how to extricate
对如何解脱有所不同的思考
yourself from that and so that's what
从那自己，所以这就是
this exercise was about so I think we
这个练习是关于，所以我想我们
have some more for each's coming up
每个人还有更多
later on in the presentation as well
稍后在演示中
yeah and that's kind of Stewart makes a
是的，这就是斯图尔特制造的
really good point because it's this
真正的好处是因为
whole idea of thinking differently
整体思考的想法
because the way I looked at it was I
因为我看的方式是
said okay so I've got these elements
说好吧，所以我有这些要素
coming through and then for each of
通过，然后为每个
those I want to do something so
那些我想做的事
immediately I've got those two words in
我马上有了这两个字
there for each of those I want to do
我想要做的每个人
something oh look there's a for each
哦，看起来每个都有一个
method I'll use the for each method and
方法我将对每种方法使用
that's not the way to do it and the way
那不是做到这一点的方式
I kind of explain this when I talk to
当我与之交谈时，我有点解释
people on other sort of lambdas and
使用其他lambda的人和
streams stuff that I do it's like if you
流的东西，我做的就像你
think if you look at for each and you
想想如果你看每个
think just I'll use for each stop and
想想我会在每个停靠站使用
think should I really be using that
认为我真的应该使用那个
because there are legitimate situations
因为有合理的情况
where you can use for each but there are
您可以在其中使用每个但有
many where you shouldn't and so using it
许多你不应该去的地方，所以用它
in a more functional way is the way to
以更实用的方式
do that so the moment you think about
这样做是为了让您一想到
using for each stop and kind of think
使用每一站和思考
about it very carefully to decide
关于它非常仔细地决定
whether that actually makes sense
这是否真的有意义
okay so right mixing internal and
好吧，所以正确混合内部和
external iteration so again you see this
外部迭代，所以再次看到
is the problem being a Java programmer
是Java程序员的问题
and not a functional programmer so here
而不是函数式程序员，所以这里
is the the back so what I wanted to do
是背面，所以我想做的是
was I had a set of data which was a
我有一组数据是
number of values for each day of the
每天的值数
year and what I wanted to do was to
年，我想做的是
group them into months so that I could
将它们分成几个月，以便我可以
build a graph of each month and then
建立每个月的图表，然后
have a bar associated with each day so I
每天都有一个酒吧，所以我
could see how much data there was for
可以看到有多少数据
that particular day so I went I needed
那一天，所以我去了，我需要
some we're grouping them by month and
一些我们按月将它们分组，
then
然后
having values for each day in that month
具有该月中每一天的值
so I started off with a very simple
所以我从一个非常简单的开始
piece of code where I said for int I
我为int所说的一段代码
equals 0 I less than 12 I plus plus good
等于0我少于12我加好
Java code simple loop and then I thought
Java代码简单循环然后我想
right so I've got a loop I'm going to
对，所以我要循环
use a stream so I put a stream inside my
使用流，所以我将流放入我的
loop and I'll say the days of the month
循环，我会说一个月的日子
for that month is the data that I've got
那个月的数据是我得到的
our critter stream I mean I've got a
我们的小动物流我是说我有一个
filter it so that I say get the month
过滤它，以便我说得到月份
and check to see if that compares
并检查是否比较
against then of course in that case you
当然，在那种情况下
know it's starting from 0 versus
知道它是从0开始
starting from 1 so we have to add 1 to I
从1开始，所以我们必须加1
in order to get the appropriate month
为了得到适当的月份
number this is where things get a little
数字这是东西有点
bit complicated so we check to see where
有点复杂，所以我们检查看看
it's the right month and then we say
这是合适的月份，然后我们说
filter that to only get the data for
进行过滤以仅获取数据
that month and then we collect it using
那个月，然后我们使用收集
a grouping by where we're getting the
根据我们得到的分组
day of the month and then the count
一个月中的某天，然后进行计数
associated with that day of the month so
与该月的某天相关，因此
that generates what we need in terms of
产生了我们所需要的
the the map that we're creating now if
我们现在创建的地图，如果
you look at that ok so that's a little
你看着那好一点
bit odd but it sort of you think to
有点奇怪，但是你觉得
yourself ok would that work and the
好的，您自己会工作的，
answer is no it won't for the simple
答案是不，这不会简单
reason that we're using I plus 1 now
我们现在使用我加1的原因
because we're in a stream we're using a
因为我们在直播中，我们正在使用
lambda expression and our expressions
lambda表达式和我们的表达式
can only reference variables from the
只能引用来自
surrounding scope if they are
如果它们是周围的范围
effectively final now because we're
现在有效地结束了，因为我们
adding 1 to I it is not effectively
给我加1这是无效的
final and also because I is changing I
最后，也是因为我正在改变
is not effectively final so we can't do
并不是有效的最终决定，所以我们不能做
that so I looked at that and I thought
所以我看着那个，我想
to myself hmmm how can we solve this
对我自己，我们该如何解决
problem I know I'll add one more line of
问题，我知道我会再增加一行
code I will set a new variable called I
代码我将设置一个名为I的新变量
and then I'll change the the loop
然后我改变循环
variable name and I'll set I to BM so
变量名，我将其设置为BM
then I is effectively final and I can
那么我实际上是最终的，我可以
get away with that you can notice that
逃脱，你可以注意到
you know I'm not really a functional
你知道我不是一个真正的功能
programmer here so clearly at this point
此时的程序员如此清晰
I is now effectively final and we can
我现在实际上是决赛，我们可以
actually get away with adding 1 to that
实际上要加1
in that case so ok that's really not the
在那种情况下，那真的不是
right way to do it so what we should be
正确的方法去做，所以我们应该
doing is using internal iteration for
做的是使用内部迭代
both the the weight what both of the
两者的重量都
loops that we
循环，我们
doing here so why don't we use streams
在这里做什么，为什么我们不使用流
for iteration and so what I could do is
进行迭代，所以我能做的是
I could do okay
我可以做的很好
let's create a stream from int stream
让我们从int流创建一个流
where we're going from 0 to 12 so that
我们将从0转到12
gives us a stream in the same way that
以相同的方式给我们一个流
we have our loop that goes from 0 to 12
我们的循环从0到12
will create a stream of intz which goes
将创建一个intz流
from 0 to 12 and then we'll use for each
从0到12，然后我们将使用每个
aha
啊哈
are we using the right thing here
我们在这里使用正确的东西吗
immediately we have to ask ourselves
立即我们必须问自己
probably not and then what we do is we
可能不是，然后我们要做的是
say okay take I and then we'll say days
说好吧带我，然后我们说几天
a month I is and then we go back to our
我一个月，然后我们回到我们的
stream for the data so now we're looping
流数据，所以现在我们循环
through the data internally and then we
通过内部数据，然后我们
do the same thing we had before so we
做我们以前做过的事情，所以我们
have filter month the R of I plus 1
过滤月份为我的R加1
collect same collector so in this case I
收集相同的收集器，所以在这种情况下，我
is a valid reference so we can get away
是有效的参考，所以我们可以逃脱
with that so this gives us some you know
这样，我们就可以知道一些
we're using iterate internal iteration
我们正在使用迭代内部迭代
for both loops but it's still pretty
对于两个循环，但仍然很漂亮
ugly code so do you want to meet me go
丑陋的代码，所以你想见我走吗
all the way through to the end and then
一直到最后
so then Stewart had to look at this and
所以斯图尔特不得不看这个
you guys mmm okay there's there some
你们好，那里有一些
better things that we can do here the
我们可以在这里做的更好的事情
first of those is to eliminate for each
首先是要消除每个
so this is the thing we don't want to be
所以这就是我们不想成为的东西
using for each in a situation like this
在这样的情况下使用每个
so what we actually do is we say okay
所以我们实际上是在说好
we're going to create a map going from
我们将创建一个从
month to a map of integers and Long's so
月到整数和Long的映射
this is the the second the internal map
这是第二张内部图
is the day of the month and the count
是一个月中的第几天
associated with that month and we'll
与该月相关联，我们将
create results so we take our data and
创建结果，以便我们获取数据并
we stream it okay and what we're going
我们流它可以，我们要去
to do is we had a map to the date okay
要做的是我们有一张日期地图
that's all good so we get the date for
一切都很好，所以我们知道了
that particular piece of data and then
那个特定的数据，然后
we're going to collect but the collect
我们要收集，但收集
changes so we use a more a better way of
变化，因此我们使用了更好的方法
doing the collector so we said collect
做收集者，所以我们说收集
we want to group by and in this case
我们想分组，在这种情况下
we're gonna use own date/time get month
我们将使用自己的日期/时间获取月份
so we get the month associated with that
所以我们得到与之相关的月份
so to group by month and then we're
所以按月分组，然后我们
going to group by the day of the month
要在每月的一天分组
and then we're going to count so this
然后我们要数一下
gives us exactly what we want in terms
给我们确切我们想要的
of a map which maps from the month to
从一个月到
the day of the month and account
每月的日期和帐户
associated with that month
与该月相关
and so that is obviously the better
所以这显然更好
stream solution so Jonah okay so this I
流解决方案，所以乔纳斯好吧，这我
get I'll tell you in a moment right but
我马上告诉你，但是
let's look at this code for a moment I
让我看一下这段代码
think this is the the nested grouping by
认为这是嵌套分组
I think throws a lot of people and it's
我认为有很多人参加，
kind of hard to come out with with a
很难拿出来
nested grouping by you know right off
您知道的嵌套分组
the top of your head but yeah I I think
你的头顶，但是我想
the way to think about it is to build
思考的方法是建立
things up incrementally so why don't we
事情逐渐增加，为什么我们不
go back to the to the very first slide
回到第一张幻灯片
that hasn't has the array
没有数组
okay yeah that's a fine one because
好的，那很好，因为
that's yeah that's logically the same
是的，在逻辑上是相同的
thing it's just yeah this is the first
是的，这是第一次
the first code that that works because
第一个有效的代码是因为
of the effectively final issue right so
有效的最终发行权
so what's not on this slide is the
所以这张幻灯片上没有的是
Declaration of this this array that's
这个数组的声明是
being assigned to and so if you if you
被分配给，所以如果你，如果你
if you look at this carefully it's it's
如果你仔细看这是
an array that has to go that has that
一个必须去的数组
has to have twelve twelve elements and
必须有十二十二个元素
there's it's I think the array is
那是我认为数组是
actually miss named but it's basically
实际上错过了命名，但基本上
an array element for each month so the
每个月的数组元素，因此
the the indexes into the array are 0
数组的索引为0
through 11 because that's what we're
到11点，因为那就是我们
getting out of the for loop and we're
摆脱for循环，我们
assigning something to each array
给每个数组分配一些东西
element based on the month and so that
基于月份的元素，这样
should think about this a little bit so
应该考虑一下
if you have an O and then the element
如果你有一个O然后是元素
type of the array is whatever you get
数组的类型就是你得到的
back from that stream and so what we're
从那条溪流回来，所以我们
doing is we're collecting using grouping
我们正在使用分组进行收集
by and so the result is each element is
通过，所以结果是每个元素是
a map right so that's that's our that's
正确的地图，这就是我们的
our count from the day of the month to
我们从一个月的天算起
sorry that's a map from the day of the
抱歉，那是从那天起的地图
month to count the count and so so in
一个月来计数，以此类推
the inner in in so that's already you
内在，所以已经是你
see the inner grouping by there so so
看到那里的内部分组等等
let's just say we're working on one
假设我们正在开发一个
month right so what this does is it goes
正确的一个月
through for that month for each day of
通过该月的每一天
the month uses the day of the month as
该月份使用当月的日期作为
as the grouping key and then the count
作为分组键，然后是计数
ends up in the value so that's that's
最终得出的值就是
where you get that that turns into your
你得到那变成你的
inner grouping by but we wrap something
内部分组依据，但我们包装了一些东西
around it which is a for loop which is
围绕它是一​​个for循环是
for each month but then the result is
每个月，但结果是
this array of entries per month which is
每月的条目数组是
this map and so if you think about an
这张地图，所以如果您考虑
array this in a different way
用不同的方式排列
this is an array of maps which first of
这是一组地图
all mixing arrays and generics is
所有混合数组和泛型是
usually pretty bad and I think you
通常很糟糕，我想你
didn't include the declaration in the
没有在
array because it's really ugly because
数组，因为它真的很丑，因为
because you have to you have to use
因为你必须使用
unsafe casts in order to allocate it but
为了分配它不安全的演员，但是
but really this this should start to
但实际上这应该开始
tell you that maybe an array is not the
告诉你，也许数组不是
right data structure for this because if
正确的数据结构，因为如果
you have an array going from 0 to 11
你有一个从0到11的数组
where each each array index represents a
其中每个数组索引代表一个
month and then you have a value stored
月，然后您存储了一个值
in that array that's actually a map it's
在那个实际上是地图的数组中
a map from a month to some value and so
从一个月到某个值的地图等等
that's where we get our outer map and so
那就是我们得到外部地图的地方
instead of looping over the array and
而不是遍历数组
actually kind of another thing that this
其实这是另一回事
does this is imagine this is very large
难道这是想象中的很大
data set this actually loops over the
数据集实际上在
entire data set 12 times and so what
整个数据集12次等等
what we really want to do is take one
我们真正想做的就是拿一个
pass over the array and say ah ok which
越过数组，然后说“好吧”
month does this belong in and classify
这个月属于和分类
it now that we have some piece of data
现在我们有了一些数据
for this month say what day of the month
这个月说几号
is this and so we're classifying it
是这个，所以我们将其分类
again and then with that item add 1 to
再次，然后与该项目加1
that count so we're doing these two
这很重要，所以我们正在做这两个
levels of classification first by month
首先按月分类
at first bite and then second by day of
第一次咬人，然后第二天
the month and that's where we get our
这个月，这就是我们得到我们的地方
two grouping buys so that the so if you
两个分组购买，因此，如果你
change the data structure from an array
从数组更改数据结构
to a map and then you can say oh we're
到地图，然后你可以说，哦，我们
classifying by months and whenever
按月分类，并随时进行分类
you're classifying by some value that
您通过某种价值进行分类
turns into a grouping by that's where
在那变成一个分组
the outermost grouping by comes from and
最外面的分组依据来自和
so why don't you why don't we wind back
所以你为什么不回头
to the to the last slide there and you
到那里的最后一张幻灯片，您
can you can see that
你能看到吗
so so I think this what's what's you
所以我想这就是你
understand see once you've you know
一旦知道就明白了
bought into the idea of grouping by as
接受了按分组的想法
classifying things into a map then here
然后将事物分类为地图
we have you know you see the first
我们知道你看到第一个
grouping by is by month second grouping
分组是按月第二分组
by is by day of month and then the count
按是按月的天数，然后是计数
is the third thing so you get this yes I
是第三件事，所以你明白了
mean it's a little complicated but it's
意思是有点复杂，但是
this nested map structure but it's much
这种嵌套的地图结构，但很多
nicer than having an array of maps I'll
比拥有一张地图要好
tell you that and the other nice thing
告诉你，还有另一件事
is that if you remember the previous
如果你还记得以前的话
slides we well what wasn't on the slide
幻灯片，我们很好，幻灯片上没有
was the initial allocation of the array
是数组的初始分配
and then the what was in the
然后是什么
intermediate code was assignments to
中间代码是对
individual array elements and so again
单个数组元素等等
back to side effects inside of for each
每个内部都有副作用
right so if we continue in that theme we
对，所以如果我们继续这个主题，我们
want to we want to we want to avoid side
想要我们想要我们想要避免的一面
effects if possible and say okay how can
可能的话说效果好吧
we construct a value that has the right
我们构造一个具有正确的价值
properties we want and so that's what
我们想要的属性，这就是
collecting does so we have all of our
收集做到了，所以我们拥有了我们所有的
stream elements they run through this
流元素通过它们运行
collector that does this nested
嵌套的收集器
classification and it builds up this
分类并建立这个
two-level map and that's the result of
两级地图，这就是
our method so no side effects in here
我们的方法，所以这里没有副作用
good okay so the next one is one of the
很好，所以下一个是其中之一
things that we did in a hands-on lab so
我们在动手实验室中所做的事情
Stuart and I have been the past of and
斯图尔特和我曾经是
today yesterday I've run hands-on labs
今天昨天我已经进行了动手实验
for streams where people get exercises
用于人们锻炼的溪流
that they can work through and they can
他们可以通过努力，他们可以
see how they work and so one of those
看看他们是如何工作的，所以其中之一
that I ran last year I think it was was
去年我跑了，我认为那是
a simple exercise the idea was you had
一个简单的练习就是你有
to concatenate the first character of
连接的第一个字符
each string in a list to generate a new
列表中的每个字符串生成一个新的
string so the input was alpha Bravo
字符串，因此输入为alpha Bravo
Charlie Delta echo Foxtrot so what we
查理·德尔塔（Charlie Delta）回响了狐步舞（Foxtrot），所以我们
were looking for was a way of getting
在寻找是一种获得
ABCDEF okay and the answer to that is
ABCDEF好的，答案是
not to use streams it actually uses the
不使用它实际上使用的流
for each method on the iterable iterable
对于每种方法在可迭代
interface so what we do is we create a
界面，所以我们要做的是创建一个
string builder and then we say input dot
字符串生成器，然后我们说输入点
for each and this is a legitimate user
对于每个人，这是一个合法用户
for each and we say append the character
对于每个，我们说追加字符
at zero to ours
在我们的零
Miller yes and then the result is simply
米勒是的，然后结果很简单
to extract the string from the
从中提取字符串
stringbuilder
字符串生成器
three lines of code does exactly what it
三行代码完全符合其要求
should do and it works perfectly so the
应该可以，并且效果很好，所以
the thing that happened was I was doing
发生的事情是我在做
this course and somebody was asking a
这门课，有人问一个
question they said well okay so that
问题他们说很好，这样
that uses that could we do it with
使用可以做到的
streams and I said well yes I suppose we
溪流，我说很好，是的，我想我们
could do it with streams let's do it
可以用流做到这一点，让我们去做
this way so a correct result where we
这样的正确结果，我们
take their input we take the stream we
接受他们的意见我们接受信息流我们
map our used substring 0 1 for this one
映射我们使用的子字符串0 1
so we mapped to the first character in
所以我们映射到中的第一个字符
the string and then we reduce it so
字符串，然后我们减少它
we'll use a reduction the reduction is
我们将使用减少量减少
where we take an initial value which is
我们取一个初始值是
an empty string and then we use an
一个空字符串，然后我们使用
accumulator which says take the the
累加器说
partial result a and the next element in
部分结果a和中的下一个元素
the stream be E and apply some
流是E并应用一些
accumulation to those so in this case
在这种情况下积累到那些
we're just doing string concatenation so
我们只是在进行字符串连接，所以
looked at that and it was like okay well
看着那个，还好吧
that doesn't solve the problem but it
那并不能解决问题，但是
doesn't do it in a very nice way because
这样做不是很好，因为
even I can see that we're doing string
甚至我看到我们在做弦乐
concatenation there so there's a lot of
串联在一起，所以有很多
intermediate objects being created and
正在创建的中间对象和
we'll have a situation where if this was
我们会遇到这样的情况
a large data set
大数据集
it'd be very inefficient certainly
这肯定是非常低效的
compared to the previous one so then the
与上一个相比，那么
question was well could we do it with a
问题很好，我们可以用
reduction using a string builder so
使用字符串生成器还原
rather than you know using a string
而不是您知道使用字符串
concatenation operation let's use a
串联操作，让我们使用
string builder so I thought right let's
字符串生成器，所以我认为正确，让我们
see if we can do that and I came up with
看看我们能否做到，我想出了
a piece of code to do that kind of
一段代码来做那种
interesting so we create a new string
有趣，所以我们创建了一个新字符串
builder and then we say take the input
建造者，然后我们说输入
stream and then we'll map it to our
流，然后将其映射到我们的
substring and then we'll reduce it but
子串，然后我们减少它，但是
this time we'll use our string builder
这次我们将使用我们的字符串生成器
in the reduction and we'll say that the
在减少，我们会说
accumulator is to append B and then
累加器将附加B，然后
returned that as a string so that
以字符串形式返回，以便
creates a new puncture result by pending
通过挂起创建新的穿刺结果
B to our string so then we the results
B到我们的字符串，那么我们得到的结果
because it's an optional we can't need
因为它是可选的，我们不需要
to return what the value of the option
返回期权的价值
is so who thinks that would work okay
是这样的，谁认为这行得通
yes good well I'm obviously not going to
是的，很好，我显然不会
ask that question if it did work am i
问这个问题我是否有用
okay so that that fails okay anybody
好的，这样失败了，每个人
want to guess what the actual result is
想猜出实际结果是什么
nope second not a different order of
不，第二个没有不同的顺序
letters now actually what you get is b c
现在收到的信件实际上是不列颠哥伦比亚省
d e f the reason for that is that if you
def的原因是，如果你
look at the reduce there you've got a
看看那里的减少
and b and i've conveniently ignored a
和b，而我已经方便地忽略了a
now a is the partial result and when you
现在a是部分结果，当您
first start processing the stream the
首先开始处理流
first partial result is the first
第一个部分结果是第一个
element in that stream so if you ignore
流中的元素，所以如果您忽略
the first partial result then you don't
第一个部分结果，那么你就不会
get a in your straight in your stream
在流中直奔
you don't get the what you need so I
你没有得到你所需要的，所以我
thought to myself I'm not going to be
自以为我不会
defeated by this there is a way to do
被此打败有办法
this using a string builder and so I
这使用字符串生成器，所以我
came up with this so I said okay let's
想出了这个，所以我说好吧
be sneaky about this let's say if a
偷偷摸摸的说，如果
which is our partial result has a length
这是我们的部分结果有一个长度
of 1 that means it's the first element
的1表示它是第一个元素
because it's only a 1 character then
因为那时只有一个字符
we'll append a to our string builder
我们将a附加到我们的字符串生成器
otherwise we ignore that and we simply
否则我们会忽略这一点，而我们只是
return there speed append B to string
返回那里速度追加B到字符串
great and that actually gives you the
很棒，实际上给了你
right result clearly that is probably
正确的结果显然是
not the best approach
不是最好的方法
so then we kind of discussed this
所以我们来讨论一下
further in the class and we said ok well
在课堂上进一步，我们说很好
rather than using an explicit reduction
而不是使用显式减少
let's use a form of reduction which is a
让我们使用一种减少形式
collection ok now you can create your
好的，现在可以创建您的收藏了
own collector so what we could do is we
自己的收藏家，所以我们能做的就是
could say let's collect and then we'll
可以说让我们收集，然后我们将
say collector dot off and we'll create a
说收集点关闭，我们将创建一个
new collector and the way you create
新收藏家和创建方式
collectors you need to provide a number
收藏家，您需要提供一个号码
of components if you like to the
如果您喜欢
collector so the first of those is the
收集器，所以第一个是
supplier what are we going to collect
供应商我们要收集什么
into so we'll say in this case it's a
因此，在这种情况下，我们会说
stringbuilder so we want to use
stringbuilder，所以我们要使用
moving on to generate a new string
继续生成一个新的字符串
builder so we use the the constructor
生成器，所以我们使用构造器
reference that's what I'm looking for
这就是我要寻找的参考
then you need an accumulator so sames
那你需要一个累加器
maybe we're doing a reduction so we need
也许我们正在减少，所以我们需要
an accumulator and in this case we want
一个累加器，在这种情况下，我们要
to append the string to the string
将字符串追加到字符串
builder great then third arguments a
建设者伟大然后第三个论点
little bit odd because you need a
有点奇怪，因为你需要一个
combiner and a combiner in this case is
合并器和合并器在这种情况下是
the same as the accumulator the reason
与蓄电池相同的原因
for having a combiner and an accumulator
具有组合器和累加器
is that this potentially could be split
可能会被拆分
into multiple threads so each thread
分成多个线程，所以每个线程
will
将
use the accumulator to generate its
使用累加器生成其
particular result and then the combiner
特定的结果，然后是组合器
is used to combine the results of each
用于合并每个结果
thread into a single result for the
线程成单个结果
collection so they could potentially be
收集，因此它们可能是
different but in this case they're
不同，但在这种情况下，它们是
they're the same and then you need a
他们是一样的，然后你需要一个
finisher which is how you generate the
整理器，这就是您生成
result from the the work that you've
从您所做的工作中得到的结果
been doing and in this case we're just
一直在做，在这种情况下，我们只是
calling the to string on that now that
现在调用to字符串
obviously works and is fine but there is
显然有效并且很好，但是有
actually a much simpler way of doing
实际上是一种更简单的方法
this which is just use collectors
这只是使用收集器
joining so use the existing collector
加入，所以使用现有的收集器
and in fact if you look at the source
实际上，如果您查看源代码
code for collectors joining what you'll
收集者加入您的代码
find is it's exactly the same as the
发现它与
previous slide so I ended up doing the
上一张幻灯片，所以我最终做了
same thing in in essence so okay so can
本质上是一样的东西，所以可以
you wind back to the beginning of this
你回头开始
scenario just a couple brief comments on
场景只是几个简短的评论
this okay so the the segment of code at
好的，所以代码段位于
the bottom is correct as as Simon
底部和西蒙一样正确
observed but it is quite inefficient
观察到，但是效率很低
because this is this is this the string
因为这是这个字符串
concatenation anti-pattern and so the
串联反模式等
problem is that when you reduce this way
问题是当您减少这种方式
the intermediate result gets copied
中间结果被复制
multiple times because it's producing
多次，因为它正在产生
strings every time and so if you have n
每次都是字符串，所以如果您有n
the strings input that are being
正在输入的字符串
concatenated this way this turns into an
通过这种方式串联起来，
order and squared problem and so this is
有序和平方问题，所以这是
a very very expensive way of of
一种非常非常昂贵的方式
concatenating strings so that's why we
连接字符串，这就是为什么我们
added the the joining method because
添加了加入方法，因为
this is a common thing and we don't want
这是很平常的事情，我们不想
people to have to write expensive
人们不得不写昂贵的东西
algorithms like this okay
这样的算法还可以
once you go to the to the really
一旦你去了真正的
complicated one couple Oh actually yeah
一对夫妇真的很复杂哦
that so that one yeah I'll just
这样我就可以
reiterate here Simon observed that if
西蒙在这里重申，如果
you have a reduction function that
你有一个减少功能
doesn't use one of its arguments it's
不使用其参数之一
very probably wrong and and and actually
很可能是错误的，而实际上
but what what you were trying to do
但是你想做什么
there which which I've also seen before
我以前也看过
in other code
用其他代码
is that well the thing that leads you to
那是引导你去的东西吗
not use one of the arguments is that
不使用参数之一是
you're doing side effects in it okay
你正在做副作用吗
right and so again this elimination of
对，如此再次消除
side effect or avoidance of side effects
副作用或避免副作用
is something that we need to keep an eye
是我们需要注意的事情
on okay so one one more slide here so so
好吧，再来一张幻灯片，这样
another one one point about the
关于另一点
reduction function is that it must be
归约函数是必须
associative and when we get to
联想，当我们到达
parallelism that'll be it that'll be an
并行性将是
issue but don't have time to go into a
问题，但没有时间讨论
full explanation of whether something is
关于某事是否的完整解释
associative but there are a lot of
联想的，但有很多
things that are and if you have
是的东西，如果你有
something that's slightly complex it
有点复杂的东西
actually moves you to go through a proof
实际使您通过证明
of of whether it's associative and if
是否具有关联性以及是否
you have side effects in your reduction
你的减少有副作用
function that proof becomes extremely
证明变得极端的功能
difficult if not impossible so once
困难，即使不是不可能，所以一次
again side effects are are to be avoided
再次避免副作用
okay why don't we move on to the next
好吧，为什么我们不继续下一个
scenario okay yeah I think we're
场景好吧，是的，我想我们是
probably not gonna get through
可能不会通过
everything in the end okay so we'll just
最后一切都好，所以我们将
do some quick performance examples so
做一些快速的性能示例，以便
one is extremely reuse good or bad so
一个是极好的复用的好坏
we've got a stream here of intz from 1
我们这里有1英寸的流
to 10 print those out so why don't we
十个打印出来，为什么我们不
reuse it and do you know make life
重用它，你知道创造生活吗
efficient well reuse that anybody think
任何人都认为有效的井再利用
that would work again I'm asking a
那会再次工作，我问一个
question which you're probably not going
你可能不会去的问题
to be so the answer is no because that
答案是肯定的，因为
will throw an illegal state exception
会抛出非法状态异常
because the stream has already already
因为流已经
been operated on or closed so you can
已开启或关闭，因此您可以
only use the stream once that's the
只使用流
important thing about that second one
关于第二个重要的事情
which is better and why so we've got
哪个更好，为什么我们有
point stream and then we're doing a
点流，然后我们做一个
filter map and well for each and so
过滤器地图，以及每个等等
we're using an explicit lambda
我们正在使用显式lambda
expression here to say that we want to
在这里表达我们要
get is this point in view invert the
得到的是这一观点倒置
point and then print it out same
点，然后打印出来一样
effective piece of code is functionally
有效的代码在功能上
the same stream filter but we this time
相同的流过滤器，但是这次
we're using the method reference rather
我们正在使用方法参考
than the lambda expression so who thinks
比lambda表达式更重要
the top one is more efficient okay who
最重要的是更有效的
thinks the bottom one is more efficient
认为最底层的效率更高
okay who thinks they're the same
好吧，谁以为他们是一样的
ha okay so the answer is that the bottom
好的，答案是最底层
one is slightly more efficient and the
一个稍微更有效，
reason for that actually if you want to
实际上，如果您想这样做的原因
learn more about that you can come to my
了解更多有关您可以来找我的信息
session this afternoon what I'm talking
会议今天下午我在说什么
about lambdas is explicitly but the the
关于lambdas是明确的，但
key point is that when a lambda gets
关键是当lambda
compiled it gets compiled in the the
编译它在
body of the lambda expression needs to
Lambda表达式的主体需要
be put into a method that's associated
放入关联的方法
with the the place where it's used and
与使用它的地方
so if we have already a method reference
所以如果我们已经有方法参考
then you don't need to put it into
那你就不用放进去了
another method reference or another
另一个方法参考或另一个
method so it saves a level of
方法，这样可以节省
indirection if you know in essence so
间接，如果您本质上知道的话
that's why it's a little bit more
这就是为什么它多一点的原因
slightly better in terms of performance
在性能方面略胜一筹
and then multi sorts okay so this is the
然后可以进行多种排序，所以这是
bad way of doing things so we what we're
做事的方式不好，所以我们是
looking is we've got some patience we've
看起来我们有一些耐心
got some information about them and so
得到了一些关于他们的信息，所以
we're saying okay if this is valid
我们说这是否有效
record then we want sort by medication
记录然后我们要按药物排序
then we want to talk by physical
那我们想通过身体说话
physician and we sort want to sort by
医生，我们排序想要排序
name so we do it in that sense the
名称，所以我们在某种意义上做到了
reality is that that would actually be
实际情况是
much better if we do it using then
如果我们这样做，那就更好了
comparing so we do the same thing in
比较，所以我们在做同样的事情
effect so we're still comparing based on
效果，因此我们仍在根据
but we have to reverse the order as well
但是我们也必须颠倒顺序
name physician medication so do you want
命名医生药物，所以要
to say parallel streams okay let's just
说并行流好吧，我们只是
talk about that briefly so parallel
这么简短地谈论一下
streams are faster surely because we're
流肯定更快，因为我们
doing things in parallel we must get a
并行做事，我们必须
better faster result unfortunately it's
不幸的是，更快更好的结果是
not guaranteed and the reason for that
不能保证，原因是
is that a parallel stream you can
是可以并行流
guarantee that there's always going to
确保永远
be more work involved because you've got
参与更多的工作，因为您有
the fork/join framework that's used
使用的fork / join框架
underneath and what you have to set up
下面以及您必须设置的内容
the framework you have to create the
您必须创建的框架
jobs that are associated with the queues
与队列关联的作业
for those threads you have to do all the
对于那些线程，您必须做所有
work and then you have to collect the
工作，然后您必须收集
results at the end so it's definitely
最后的结果，所以绝对
gonna be more work it might happen or
可能会做更多的工作，或者
might complete more quickly a couple of
可能会更快完成
important facts about parallel streams
关于并行流的重要事实
are the fact that they use the common
是他们使用共同点的事实
fork/join pool so there's a fork/join
叉/连接池，所以有一个叉/连接
pool that's created when the JVM starts
JVM启动时创建的池
up and they will all you in terms of
起来，他们会在
parallel streams they will always use
他们将始终使用的并行流
the fork/join pool in terms of the
分叉/联接池
number of CPUs that that uses it
使用它的CPU数量
defaults to the number of cores or CPUs
默认为内核或CPU的数量
that
那
reported by the operating system some
操作系统报告的一些
people have said it's twice that number
人们说这是这个数字的两倍
some people say it's that another plus
有人说这是另一个优点
one if you look at the source code it is
一个，如果你看一下源代码就是
actually the number of CPUs reported by
实际报告的CPU数量
the operating system one point that's
操作系统的一点是
interesting about that is if you're
有趣的是，如果你是
using JDK 8 I'm not sure if this is
使用JDK 8我不确定这是否是
being back ported but if you're using
被反向移植，但如果您使用的是
JDK 8 that's not see group aware which
JDK 8无法识别组
means if you're using a docker container
表示如果您使用的是Docker容器
and you run your JVM within that docker
然后您在该docker中运行JVM
container when it sets up the full joint
设置完整关节时的容器
pool and this is the same for the memory
池，这对于内存是相同的
that it uses for the heap as well it's
它也用于堆
going to get the results for the whole
将获得整个结果
machine not for the container JDK 9 has
机器不是用于容器JDK 9的
had some changes so JDK 9 on Linux is
进行了一些更改，因此Linux上的JDK 9是
now container aware okay so the last
现在容器知道了，所以最后
last example very quickly because we've
最后一个例子很快，因为我们已经
got about two minutes nesting parallel
大约嵌套了两分钟
streams this is a really bad idea
流这是一个非常糟糕的主意
because we're using the same fork/join
因为我们使用相同的fork / join
pool which means that although we have
池，这意味着尽管我们有
separate queues so we don't get any
单独的队列，所以我们什么也没得到
corruption of data we're trying to use
我们试图使用的数据损坏
the same set of threads to do the nested
同一套线程来做嵌套
parallel stream and you end up with
并行流，您最终得到
effectively worst performance because
实际上是最差的性能，因为
you're trying to reuse those threads but
您正在尝试重用这些线程，但是
so rather than having separate sets of
因此，不要将它们分开
threads associated with the different
与不同的线程相关联
parallel streams it's going to be worse
并行流会变得更糟
in case of in the case of performance
在表演的情况下
there is a way around this
有办法解决
which is you create your own fork/join
这是您创建自己的fork / join
pool so you can actually create for
池，以便您实际上可以为
joint tasks using a custom pool of how
使用如何
many threads you want and then you
你想要很多线程，然后你
submit your parallel stream task to that
提交并行任务
and that will use a separate set of
这将使用单独的一组
threads so you can potentially get
线程，因此您可能会得到
better performance but you had something
更好的表现，但是你有一些东西
to say about that can you yeah a couple
可以这样说吗
things about this technique here so so
这种技术的事情在这里如此
one is if you find yourself wanting to
一种是如果您发现自己想要
use your own fork/join pool I think if
用你自己的fork / join池，我想如果
you think very carefully about it the
您会非常仔细地考虑
first is that this is really an
首先是这真的是
implementation specific behavior which
具体实施行为
is that if you submit a task to a
是如果您将任务提交给
fork/join pool any streams processing
派生/加入池任何流处理
that's that's done within that task will
那就是在该任务中完成的
will be executed in the same fork/join
将在同一fork / join中执行
pool so that's that's how this works but
池，这就是它的工作原理，但是
that's not guaranteed by the spec that's
规范并不能保证
just how the implementation works today
今天的实施方式
certainly I mean for all of JDK agents
当然，对于所有JDK代理来说，我的意思是
worked that way and it's at this point
这样工作，就在此时
it's not going to change but it might
它不会改变，但是可能
change in the future release the second
将来的变化发布第二
thing is it's like well you might you
事情是这样，你也许会
might think okay well I'm gonna want to
可能会觉得很好，我要
control this so I'm going to create my
控制这个，所以我要创建我的
own fork/join pool but you should be
拥有自己的fork / join池，但是您应该
very careful because if you start
非常小心，因为如果您开始
creating fork/join pools all over your
在您的整个范围内创建派生/联接池
code and they have hard-coded constants
代码，并且它们具有硬编码的常量
in here you know somebody's gonna run
在这里，你知道有人会跑
this on a 24 core machine and saying why
这在24核计算机上并说为什么
am I only gonna get 4x speed up so or
我只会得到4倍的速度吗？
somebody runs it on a few core machines
有人在一些核心机器上运行它
and there are thread contention going on
并且正在进行线程争用
because everybody's created his own
因为每个人都创造了自己的
fork/join pool each of which thinks it
每个人都认为的fork / join池
owns the whole machine or container or
拥有整个机器或容器，或
whatever so I mean this this is a valid
不管怎样，我的意思是这是有效的
technique if you're experimenting and if
技术，如果您正在尝试，并且
you're very very careful about how you
您对自己的做法非常谨慎
deploy it but it's something too many
部署它，但是太多了
things to be careful about here okay so
这里要注意的事情还可以
so that is basically it
所以基本上就是这样
so in conclusion streams are very
因此总的来说，信息流非常
powerful but with great power comes
强大但强大
great responsibility and the important
责任重大
thing that hopefully you've got from
希望你从那里得到的东西
this is trying not to think imperatively
这是试图不要命令式地思考
try not to think in terms of loops
尽量不要以循环的方式思考
because whenever you think of for each
因为每当你想到每个
you need to step back and say is that
您需要退后一步说
the way that you should do it and as
你应该做的方式以及
Stewart said several times during the
斯图尔特在
presentation side-effects are the things
演示文稿的副作用是东西
to be avoided if you can avoid those at
如果可以避免的话可以避免
all costs then then do so part of this
然后所有的费用都要做
the power of streams is the clarity of
流的力量在于
the code don't be tempted like I was to
该代码不要像我那样被诱惑
go and try and squash everything into
去尝试把所有东西都塞进去
the smallest possible number of lines
尽可能少的行数
make it readable make it understandable
使其可读性使其易于理解
by other people and as we just explained
由其他人，正如我们刚才解释的
parallel doesn't necessarily mean faster
并行不一定意味着更快
so I think that that's you know you've
所以我认为那是你知道你已经
got a couple of key key takeaway if you
如果您有几个关键要点
find yourself writing for each with side
发现自己一边写一边
effects look at collectors so thank you
效果看收藏家，谢谢
very much
非常
you
您